



 

   //Questions array

   let questions = [

    {

         number:1,

         question: "___ is the study of the shapes and behavior of sentences",

         answer : "Syntax",

         options : [

                          "Syntax",

                          "Morphology",

                          "Semantics",

                          "Linguistics"

                        ]

    

    },

    {

         number:2,

         question: "___ is the basic unit of thought",

         answer : "Sentence",

         options : [

                          "Phrase",

                          "Sentence",

                          "Clause",

                          "Fragment"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:3,

         question: "The information given about the subject in the sentence is called",

         answer : "Predicate",

         options : [

                          "Fragment",

                          "Modifier",

                          "Complement",

                          "Predicate"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:4,

         question: "My parents live in Abuja. This is __ type of sentence",

         answer : "Simple Sentence",

         options : [

                          "Simple Sentence",

                          "Compound complex sentence",

                          "Compound sentence",

                          "Complex sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:5,

         question: "I knew that James was ill, but I didn't know he suffered from smallpox. What type of sentence is this",

         answer : "Compound complex sentence",

         options : [

                          "Simple Sentence",

                          "Compound sentence",

                          "Complex sentence",

                          "Compound complex sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:6,

         question: "I will buy you a car, if you pass your exam. This is what type of sentence",

         answer : "Complex sentence",

         options : [

                          "Simple Sentence",

                          "Compound sentence",

                          "Complex sentence",

                          "Compound complex sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:7,

         question: "The boy came in and she shut the door. What type of sentence is this",

         answer : "Compound sentence",

         options : [

                          "Simple Sentence",

                          "Compound sentence",

                          "Complex sentence",

                          "Compound complex sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:8,

         question: "A compound sentence is made up of two simple sentence is joined by ___",

         answer : "Coordinating conjunction",

         options : [

                          "Coordinating conjunction",

                          "Determiner",

                          "Post quantifier",

                          "Subordinate conjunction"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:9,

         question: "Which of these is not a sentence type according to function",

         answer : "Expository sentence",

         options : [

                          "Declarative sentence",

                          "Interrogative sentence",

                          "Expository sentence",

                          "Imperative sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:10,

         question: "__ is used to issue out command",

         answer : "Imperative sentence",

         options : [

                          "Declarative sentence",

                          "Interrogative sentence",

                          "Expository sentence",

                          "Imperative sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:11,

         question: "Interrogative sentence is written in ___",

         answer : "Inverted order",

         options : [

                          "Assertive form",

                          "Inverted order",

                          "Syntactic category",

                          "Complex sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:12,

         question: "___ type of sentence states a fact or makes an assertion",

         answer : "Declarative sentence",

         options : [

                          "Declarative sentence",

                          "Interrogative sentence",

                          "Expository sentence",

                          "Imperative sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:13,

         question: "___ suggest that the speaker is irritated",

         answer : "Forceful imperative",

         options : [

                          "Negative imperative",

                          "Mild imperative",

                          "Single word imperative",

                          "Forceful imperative"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:14,

         question: "An incomplete sentence is called __",

         answer : "Sentence fragment",

         options : [

                          "Phrase",

                          "Sentence fragment",

                          "Clause",

                          "Determiners"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:15,

         question: "___ emphasizes what should not be done",

         answer : "Negative imperative",

         options : [

                          "Negative imperative",

                          "Mild imperative",

                          "Single word imperative",

                          "Forceful imperative"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:16,

         question: "You made it! This is __ type of sentence",

         answer : "Exclamatory sentence",

         options : [

                          "Declarative sentence",

                          "Interrogative sentence",

                          "Exclamatory sentence",

                          "Imperative sentence"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:17,

         question: "Complex sentences are joined with a ___",

         answer : "Subordinate conjunction",

         options : [

                          "Coordinating conjunction",

                          "Determiner",

                          "Post quantifier",

                          "Subordinate conjunction"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:18,

         question: "Shut the door! What type of imperative is this",

         answer : "Single word imperative",

         options : [

                          "Negative imperative",

                          "Mild imperative",

                          "Single word imperative",

                          "Forceful imperative"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:19,

         question: "___ imperatives have the implied subject â€˜you`",

         answer : "Single word imperative",

         options : [

                          "Negative imperative",

                          "Mild imperatives",

                          "Single word imperative",

                          "Forceful imperative"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:20,

         question: "Although it started to rain, we still made it to the revival. This is what type of fragment",

         answer : "Dependent word fragment",

         options : [

                          "Dependent word fragment",

                          "ING fragment",

                          "Single word fragment",

                          "Group of words without finite verbs"  

                          ]

    

    }

     ];   